<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:48:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automatically annotated motion tracking identifies a distinct social behavioral profile following chronic social defeat stress</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/blog/csds_ncomms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/blog/csds_ncomms/</guid>
      <description>Here, we used our DeepOF software to gain novel insights into the social behavior of mice following chronic social defeat stress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepOF</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/software/deepof/deepof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/software/deepof/deepof/</guid>
      <description>A suite for postprocessing time-series extracted from videos of freely moving rodents using DeepLabCut and SLEAP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal learning in clinical proteomics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/blog/amr_multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/blog/amr_multimodal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neural Information Processing Systems 2023</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/blog/neurips23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/blog/neurips23/</guid>
      <description>My impressions, thoughts, and favourite papers on the 2023 edition of NeurIPS, which I attended in person in New Orleans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Probabilistic AI summer school 2024</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/blog/probai24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/blog/probai24/</guid>
      <description>My impressions and thoughts on the Tropical Probabilistic AI summer school 2024, which I had the pleasure to attend in person!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me </title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:48:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! You have reached my digital home. Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find content about my professional life, including scientific publications, projects, software, and (soon) general interest blog entries.
My name is Lucas Miranda. I was born and raised in Buenos Aires, Argentina, where I studied molecular biology and bioinformatics at the University of Buenos Aires. I recently completed my doctorate at the Technical University of Munich, directed by Bertram Müller-Myhsok at the Max Planck Institute of Psychiatry (I will upload my thesis as soon as it&amp;rsquo;s published!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/refs/</guid>
      <description>2024 J Bordes, T Bajaj, L Miranda, L van Doeselaar, L Brix, S Narayan, H Yang, S Mitra, V Kovarova, M Springer, K Kleigrewe, B Müller-Myhsok, N Gassen, MV Schmidt. &amp;ldquo;Sex-specific fear acquisition following early life stress is linked to amygdala glutamate metabolism.&amp;rdquo;, preprint in bioRxiv. Link to paper. 2023 A Kos &amp;amp; JP Lopez et al. &amp;ldquo;Early life adversity shapes social subordination and cell type–specific transcriptomic patterning in the ventral hippocampus&amp;rdquo;, in Science Advances.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
